<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>free on Merijn Geurts</title><link>https://merijng.github.io/en/tags/free/</link><description>Recent content in free on Merijn Geurts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>nl-NL</language><copyright>Merijn Geurts</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://merijng.github.io/en/tags/free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Free 'Spotify Premium' Alternative with Brave and YouTube Music</title><link>https://merijng.github.io/en/posts/free-spotify-premium-alternative/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://merijng.github.io/en/posts/free-spotify-premium-alternative/</guid><description>Tired of the monthly fees for music streaming services like Spotify Premium, but still want to listen to your favorite songs without interruptions? There&amp;rsquo;s a smart and completely legal way to get a similar premium experience, and it&amp;rsquo;s entirely free. All you need is the Brave browser and a YouTube account.
In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll explain how you can use this combination to enjoy YouTube Music without annoying ads.
Why This Method Works: The Power of Brave The secret behind this method is the Brave browser.</description><content>&lt;p>Tired of the monthly fees for music streaming services like Spotify Premium, but still want to listen to your favorite songs without interruptions? There&amp;rsquo;s a smart and completely legal way to get a similar premium experience, and it&amp;rsquo;s entirely free. All you need is the Brave browser and a YouTube account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll explain how you can use this combination to enjoy YouTube Music without annoying ads.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-this-method-works-the-power-of-brave">Why This Method Works: The Power of Brave&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The secret behind this method is the &lt;strong>Brave browser&lt;/strong>. Brave is a web browser built with a focus on privacy and security. One of its key features is the built-in ad and tracker blocker, called &lt;strong>Brave Shields&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This blocker does exactly what its name suggests: it automatically blocks ads and trackers on the websites you visit. This also applies to the audio and video ads on YouTube and YouTube Music.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="step-by-step-guide-listen-to-music-for-free-in-4-steps">Step-by-Step Guide: Listen to Music for Free in 4 Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Setting it up is surprisingly simple and only takes a few minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="step-1-install-the-brave-browser">Step 1: Install the Brave Browser&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re not already using Brave, now is the time to start.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Go to the official website: &lt;a href="https://brave.com">brave.com&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download and install the browser for your operating system (Windows, macOS, Linux).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Brave works just like Chrome or Firefox, so switching is easy. You can even import your bookmarks and extensions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="step-2-go-to-youtube-music">Step 2: Go to YouTube Music&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Open the newly installed Brave browser and navigate to YouTube Music.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Website:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://music.youtube.com">music.youtube.com&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Log in with your standard Google or YouTube account. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a special subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="step-3-optional-add-to-your-home-screen">Step 3 (Optional): Add to Your Home Screen&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For an app-like experience, you can place a shortcut to YouTube Music on your device. This makes opening it as easy as a regular app.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On desktop:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click the icon on the right side of the address bar (usually a screen with an arrow).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirm the installation. YouTube Music will now appear as an app in its own window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On Android:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Tap the menu icon (three dots).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Install app&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Add to Home screen&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirm the installation. The shortcut will now appear on your home screen.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="step-4-enjoy-uninterrupted-music">Step 4: Enjoy Uninterrupted Music&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it! Find your favorite artists, albums, or playlists and start listening. You&amp;rsquo;ll notice that the ads that normally play between songs are completely gone. Brave Shields blocks them in the background, giving you a seamless listening experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="advantages-of-this-approach">Advantages of This Approach&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Completely free:&lt;/strong> No monthly subscription fees.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No ads:&lt;/strong> Enjoy music without interruptions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Huge music library:&lt;/strong> Access to the gigantic catalog of YouTube Music.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enhanced privacy:&lt;/strong> Brave not only blocks ads but also online trackers that monitor your browsing behavior.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Works on desktop and mobile:&lt;/strong> This method works great on your computer and also in the mobile Brave app for Android.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="are-there-any-downsides">Are There Any Downsides?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While this is a fantastic alternative, there are a few Spotify Premium features you&amp;rsquo;ll miss:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Offline downloads:&lt;/strong> You can&amp;rsquo;t download music for offline use without a YouTube Premium subscription.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Audio quality:&lt;/strong> The default audio quality on YouTube Music is good, but audiophiles might prefer the higher bitrate options of paid services.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limited background playback on iOS:&lt;/strong> As mentioned, on an iPhone or iPad, the music stops if you leave the Brave app or lock the screen. This is a limitation of Apple&amp;rsquo;s operating system, not Brave. Background playback does work on Android.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For anyone who primarily listens to music on a computer or Android phone and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need offline downloads, the combination of Brave and YouTube Music is the perfect free alternative to Spotify Premium. You&amp;rsquo;ll save money, protect your privacy, and enjoy an uninterrupted stream of your favorite music. Try it for yourself!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>